in this section we will discuss high and
low approach plates at faa.gov website
you can obtain pdf version approach
plates both high and low also IFR charts
both high and low
so Sky vector and foreflight they use
this as the ultimate source for their
for their plates and charts and they
printed NGA High approach Playbook East
this is a first approach procedure in
Atlantic City the high ILS Runway one
three approach taking this plate in
segments the first the top segment
includes the approach title the the
airport identifier some Navi data trying
to approach course notes about the
runway 10 000 feet testosterone Zone
elevation and Airport elevation notes
all in a row and the Trouble T which
indicates taking off out of there
there'll be some issues with with
obstructions
lighting system is depicted next the A5
okay the dot above it remember that dot
indicates sequence flashes strobe lights
and then missed approach procedure in a
narrative format
frequencies in order of usage for Adis
approach control tower Ground Control
clearance delivery and if I have radar
approaches on high plate we'll show that
after the frequencies and a kind of
radar approach they have either ASR or
par here is the plan view for this
approach we have a two scale Circle 20
mile circle there items are shown to
scale inside that circle like the
coastline
obstructions a restricted area
and notice what obstruction is a tower
or something 589 feet to the west of the
airport that's an MSL number
we also show a handy holding entry
diagram for initial approach fix holding
mint safe altitudes and Emer safe
altitudes
in the mid-safe altitude shown at the
right based on a 25 mile circle around
the navade that describes the approach
can be divided up to four quadrants
which two in this case so men's safe is
2100 100 feet to the North 1800 feet to
the South
gives you a thousand feet obstruction
clearance
the Emer safe altitude remember that
goes out to 100 miles and that gives you
a thousand feet obstruction clearance
and kind of flat terrain it goes up to
2000 feet of instruction clearance and
designated mountainous Terrain
here we have the profile view of the ILS
High ILS 130 into Atlantic City
and you see first the small Airport
diagram
on the right side shows the front of the
approach course heading into the runway
lighting system they have they're
available the A5 with a DOT above it
from the dot meaning strobe lights
without a approach lighting system
interesting gear location of that Runway
and missed approach procedure shown a
pictorial format it's the same as the
approach procedure it should be the same
as you saw in the top part of the plate
in a narrative description here it's in
a pictorial display which makes it easy
to see and comprehend at a glance what
we need to do at missed approach
and the profile view here altitude
restrictions are pretty straightforward
client sub-intercept altitude on this
one is 1600 feet
and we see the Glide slope is three
degrees below that TCH threshold
Crossing height 58 feet an AGL number
and the minimal lines straight in ILS
Runner 1-3 Star by that there's some
note related to that you want to check
that out
the decision altitude of the approach
there 275 feet
uh visibility requirements 18 rbr
so 18 rbr would not be good enough for
cnaf 3710 single pilot rolls that
requires no lower than 24 rvr which is
equivalent to half a mile
the height of a touchdown 200 feet other
weather minimums to the far right there
200 and a half that's actually the
military weather man so we would use for
this approach
then we have the localizer running one
three approach also Stars by that see
what notes that refers to
and for category C MDA 420 feet 24 rbr
for legal as far as 3710 is concerned
345 feet it's height above touchdown and
weather bends again for military
parentheses 400 and a half
they also have a circling approach so my
shoot this High ILS one three and circle
to land on maybe 2-2 or some other
runway in that case we'll be using an
MDA of 540 feet mile and a half
prevailing visibility requirements and
the 465 number instead of hydrobo
touchdown now for the circling procedure
that's referring to the height above
Airport
the inoperative components table located
in the front part of approach playbooks
so an approach is developed and minimas
are established for that given approach
it's assumed that all components of that
approach are operational including
Lighting systems
in the case of ILS Runway 1-3 at
Atlantic City the lighting system they
have available there is malsr
it's an ILS than 1800 rvr
so in this case the standard correction
to make would be that lighting system is
out of service increase rbr to the 4000
which is equivalent to three-fourths of
a mile
that agrees with a note on the approach
plate page for the ils-13 at Atlantic
City
sometimes notes in the approach play
page will have different corrections to
make for a given lighting system
component that a service
here is the legend for the small Airport
diagram an airport sketch on approach
play pages and we see we have
first
resting gear data unidirectional or
bi-directional or jet barriers
a displaced threshold indication like
those oval circular circles
so displaced threshold as a portion of
the runway that can be used for for your
takeoff role or for landing rollouts but
it cannot be your touchdown point on the
runway because it's not hardened enough
for aircraft Landings
how much parts are depicted in the in
this case they had the Box the hs1 in it
instruction data around the airport
rotating Beacon symbology
and Runway gradient like upslope or down
slope
so in some runways have it slide up
slower slight down slope an example
would be home field normally one left
full stopping on one left we have a
slight upslope gradient which makes
braking somewhat easier on your rollout
there
here's a full page Airport diagram for
Atlantic City
one of the handy features of the full
page diagram is the latitude longitude
Grid or relay
so with this one thing we could do is
calculate a latitudinal longitude for
the approach end of Runway 31 for
instance we're going to land there so
using that great overlay you would
calculate for latitude will be North 39
degrees
27.1 minutes
and West 74 degrees
33.6 minutes
makes a pretty accurate Waypoint okay
pretty good for persistent approaches or
maybe just flying a VFR Landing pattern
around the airport on the full page
diagram for Atlantic City in the
previous slide we noticed a hot spot
near the intersection of runways two two
and three one labeled hotspot one
in the front part of approach blade
books there's a segment entitled
hotspots where we can look up airports
alphabetically
so for instance Atlantic City they're
hot spot one so there's runways one
three three one it takes away a and
Runway is zero four two and takes away B
so hot spots in general are depicted
when in the past there's been historical
confusion due to Runway markings or
taxiway markings lead and hold short
operations information it's in a segment
in the front part of the approach
Playbook again we can look up airports
alphabetically
and we can see that if we were going to
for instance land on Runway three one
and hold short at the intersection of
runways zero four slash two two that
rollout distance would allow you 5750
feet
however t45s are not really authorized
for land in old short operations here's
a low approach plate for the attack and
Runway one six left at Jackson
Mississippi
so the features are basically the same
on a low approach plate as you see in a
high approach plate
as you can see in this one though
sometimes in low approach plates they
eliminate the emergency safe altitude
they haven't been safe altitude but no
emergency safe altitude
in that case if we were flying with a
low chart which we should be we can see
the oroka altitude circled in this
diagram image
and that's 2700 feet so that's off-road
obstruction clearance altitude
it has the same parameters as the Emer
safe altitude giving you a thousand feet
obstruction clearance in flat terrain
two thousand feet obstruction clearancy
designated mountainous areas
pilot controlled Lighting systems
designated by the lighting symbology
being a black circle and white lettering
so on the appropriate frequency with my
clicks we can increase or decrease
Runway lighting intensity as was
mentioned at the nav 0 1 0 1 like share
some approach plates include topography
like chart features for approaches and
say mountainous terrain so in this case
Jackson Hole ILS Yankee Runway one nine
Final Approach course takes us through a
valley with pretty high terrain either
side of our Final Approach course here's
the Final Approach segment of the ILS
approach Runway 4 at Tuscaloosa Alabama
we notice the Glide slope intercept
altitude 1500 feet or above also at the
outer marker a number above that 1433
that reflects the altitude of the Glide
slope and MSL terms at that point over
the ground
it's a method for checking light slope
validity
so we intercept line path and 1500 feet
or above somewhere prior to the outer
marker when you get down to the outer
marker if we have a centered up line
path needle we want to see 1433
if we are looking at some different
number where the centered up blind path
needle say looking at 1200 feet instead
of 1433
here's some issue with that Glide slope
transmission it could be a Glide slope
transmitter error it could be now
temperature setting error could be a
number of things but in any case you may
not want to continue on a Precision
approach if your line slope altitude
doesn't match up at that outer marker
there you may want to transition to a
localized approach in doing so make sure
that we start the clock at that Final
Approach fix at the outer marker on a
local Arts approach we would need to
chime to a missed approach Point using
the timing table in the bottom right of
the approach play page here's the legend
section for the ILS located in all
approach playbooks in the front part
Legend area
here we note the the Glide slope
altitude at the outer marker or Final
Touch fix we also have a non-precision
approach Legend and the front part of
approach blade books
in this case of Interest we see the
vertical descent angle 2.93 degrees
from the Final Approach fix to a point
of the runway at a threshold Crossing
height of 50 feet the inside back cover
of approach flight books I have this
descent gradient table
so using this we can calculate a vsi to
maintain a certain Glide path at a given
ground speed
in our example here we had a ground
speed of 120 knots and a three degree
Glide path in theory it would take about
637 feet per minute to maintain that
Three Degree Glide path here we find the
radar Minima section for radar
approaches we can look up the Airfield
alphabetically like Meridian Nas for
example
let me say for the par 319 left has a
Glide slope of three degrees threshold
Crossing height of 45 feet AGL
RPI running point of intercept 1057 feet
we would have touched down if we flew
the Glide path right down a touchdown
for all categories of aircraft the
decision altitude that should be is 416
feet giving you a height of a touchdown
of 100 feet
and whether it's minimums 100 feet
ceiling and half a mile visibility
so the 100 feet high about touchdown
would not be adequate for single pilot
rules in our case so we need to add 100
feet to that to make that a 200 foot
height of our touchdown
also add that 100 feature decision
altitude
which makes your decision enough to do
now 5 16 feet for this approach for
single pilot purposes we also have an
approach called a par without Glide
slope which is basically an ASR but now
they're using the Precision radar which
has better Azimuth resolution so you
find somewhat lower weather requirements
than on a straight ASR approach
but otherwise technique wise we would
fly that just like an ASR normal ASR
means slightly higher in some cases
because they're using the surveillance
radar
and the circling minibus so should a GCA
of some kind or some Runway circular
line or some other Runway Runway at the
airport
and in this case for all runways in
different categories we would use for
category C and MDA of 840 feet and an
840 feet Circle to land so you get to a
point where you can start a landing
profile descent